练习 1-13：个人练习。听到提示和哔声后，练习说这些句子。
Exercise 1-13. Individual Practice. Practice saying the sentences after the
你只有很短的时间回答，
suggestion and the beep tone. You'll be given only a short time in which to reply,
所以不能悠闲地想太多。你一听到
so you won't have the leisure to overthink. Start speaking as soon as you
提示音就开始说，因为几秒钟后我就会说出这个句子。第一，
hear the tone, because I'll be saying the sentence only a few seconds later. 1.
表达“听起来确实像正在下雨”这个信息。
Convey the information that it really does sound as if rain is falling.
第二，表达一种观点：虽然听起来像下雨，但也可能是别的东西。
2. Convey the opinion that, although it has the sound of rain, it may be something else.
第三，表达某人对雨和雪有不同感受。
3. Convey the different feelings that someone has about rain and snow.
第四，表达现在下雨是不可能的这个事实。
4. Convey the fact that rain is an impossibility right now.
自己把这四个句子练习十遍。等你熟悉了
Practice the four sentences on your own ten times. Once you're familiar with
移动重音并感受到意思如何变化之后，再继续
moving the stress around and feeling how the meaning changes, continue with the
下一个练习。
next exercise.